# questions = [
#   {"question": "Which command is used to list all files and directories in Linux?", "ans": 1},
#   {"question": "Which command is used to change the current directory in Linux?", "ans": 2},
#   {"question": "What is the command to display the current working directory?", "ans": 3},
#   {"question": "Which command is used to move or rename files in Linux?", "ans": 2},
#   {"question": "What is the command to view the contents of a file in Linux?", "ans": 1},
#   {"question": "Which command is used to remove a file in Linux?", "ans": 2},
#   {"question": "What is the command to create a new directory in Linux?", "ans": 1},
#   {"question": "Which command is used to copy files or directories in Linux?", "ans": 2},
#   {"question": "What is the command to display the manual of any command in Linux?", "ans": 3},
#   {"question": "Which command is used to display the system's network configuration?", "ans": 2}
# ]


questions = [
  {"question": "You want to list all the files and directories in your current working directory. Which command will you use?", "ans": "ls"},
  {"question": "You need to navigate to a different directory to work on a project. Which command will allow you to change directories?", "ans": "cd"},
  {"question": "You are unsure which directory you are currently in. How can you display your present working directory?", "ans": "pwd"},
  {"question": "You need to move a file to another directory or rename it. Which command should you use?", "ans": "mv"},
  {"question": "You want to open a file in your directory and view its contents. Which command will allow you to do that?", "ans": "cat"},
  {"question": "You want to remove a file you no longer need. Which command should you use to delete it?", "ans": "rm"},
  {"question": "You need to create a new directory for organizing your project files. Which command will you use?", "ans": "mkdir"},
  {"question": "You want to copy files from one directory to another. Which command will let you copy files?", "ans": "cp"},
  {"question": "You need help with a specific command and want to check its manual. Which command should you use?", "ans": "man"},
  {"question": "You want to check the network configuration of your system. Which command will display the network settings?", "ans": "ifconfig"}
]

